

FARHAD MALEKI

IOS Developer, Computer Network Engineer

+971-585-581-618 | Farhad.maleki1618@outlook.com | https://github.com/Farhad1618

Profile

iOS developer with 5 years of experience in Swift. Published 4 apps, with 2 more in development, and 3 pending research paper on Network Intrusion Detection. Also developed security software to detect cyber attacks. Seeking a challenging role in a fast-paced environment.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Network Engineering (Canadian University Dubai)

Dubai 2023

Experience

Swift space *IOS developer*

2021-2023

Worked as a key developer on a team, implementing features and solving tasks across four different iOS
applications.

Storage solution IOS Junior developer

2023 - 2023

• Developed a warehouse management app that increased efficiency by 45%, reduced operating costs by 20%, and simplified tasks for employees.

Stema Institute IOS developer | IOS instructor

2022-2022

• As a junior developer, solution-orientedly controlled DJ drones using Swift while also mentoring 80+ freshman students in Swift programming, demonstrating strong communication skills.

AMAL Counseling project management | IT

2018 - 2021

• Steered IT projects to success as a Project Manager, adept at solving complex IT challenges and streamlining operations.

Applications developed

Skills

Programming languages

- Purple finance a financial management app.
- Created a minimal CRM for ML.
- Developed a network intrusion detection system.
- Made an ML-based client booking app.
- Designed a student booking system.
- Programmed a drone control app.
- Recreated a Twitter-like platform.
- RFID office security system

- SKIIIS
- Proficient in Swift programming Language
- Familiarity with RESTful APIs and third-party libraries
- Core Data
- Algorithms
- Firebase
- MVC Architecture
- MMV Architecture

- Swift
 - SwiftUI
 - Objective-C
 - Python
- Java Script

Languages

- **English**
- Arabic
- Farsi